A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare Interests - Youth, Series R FA327
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Child Welfare
  - Child Welfare - Child Welfare Societies - National Child Welfare Associations, 1924-1942 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    Small gifts by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Child Welfare - Child Welfare Societies - Mayor LaGuardia Recreational Program, 1934-1938 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $10,000.
  - Child Welfare - Child Welfare Societies - Child Welfare League of America, 1924-1961 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    Small contributions by family members.
  - Child Welfare - Child Welfare Societies - Child Welfare League of America, 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 54A)
  - Child Welfare - Children's Welfare Federation, 1928-1951 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    Organized primarily for collection and sale of mothers' milk for sick children. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed for two years after Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial liquidated. Later appeals denied. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    140.1
  - Child Welfare - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1927-1940 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    Organized to handle information and bequests; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to annual budget at beginning; interest waned, and later appeals denied. Contributions through Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Mary French Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson.
    140.2
  - Child Welfare - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1941-1960 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Organized to handle information and bequests; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to annual budget at beginning; interest waned, and later appeals denied. Contributions through Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Mary French Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Child Welfare - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1948-1960 (Box 6, Folder 0057A)
  - Child Welfare - Save the Children Federation, 1933-1957 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    Organized to distribute clothing, food, books to destitute children in Southern Highlands; shifted interest to Europe because of the war; small contributions by Mary French Rockefeller. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller, Mary Clark Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    140.3
  - Child Welfare - Save the Children Federation, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Child Welfare - Save the Children Federation - England, 1930-1941 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    Appeals declined.
    See also Box 46, Folder 509.
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village, 1931-1949 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    Dobbs Ferry protective home and training school for maladjusted boys; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $50,000 in 1952. Most appeals declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    140.4
    See also Box 46, Folder 510.
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village, 1949-1960 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    Dobbs Ferry protective home and training school for maladjusted boys; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $50,000 in 1952. Most appeals declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 0062A)
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village - Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller Correspondence and Contributions, 1936-1961 (Box 7, Folder 0062B)
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Contributions, 1930-1942 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Contributions, 1942-1961 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Child Welfare - White House Conferences on Children, 1940-1958 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    Newspaper clippings.
    140.5
  - Child Welfare - Spence-Chapin Adoptive Service, 1936-1951 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    Contributions by Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller; other appeals declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    140.6
  - Child Welfare - Spence-Chapin Adoptive Service, 1952-1961 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Child Welfare - Spence-Chapin Adoptive Service, 1952-1961 (Box 7, Folder 0067A)
  - Child Welfare - American Parents Committee, 1946-1956 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    A lobbying group seeking to influence federal legislation regarding child welfare. Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial subsidized "Parents Magazine" in its first few years. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    140.7
  - Child Welfare - Northside Center for Child Development, Inc., 1948-1960 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    Small contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller to Harlem youth center. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Max Ascolin.
    140.8
  - Child Welfare - Citizens' Committee on Children of New York City, 1945-1955 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    140.9
  - Child Welfare - Citizens' Committee on Children of New York City, 1955-1960 (Box 7, Folder 0070A)
  - Child Welfare - Windham Childrens' Service, 1950-1961 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    Provided temporary care of dependent and delinquent children. Contributions by Mary French Rockefeller. Correspondents include Mary French Rockefeller.
    140.10
  - Child Welfare - Child Study Association of America, 1930-1961 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    Association with Society of Ethical Culture to train parents in training children. Contributions by Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Dana S. Creel.
    140.11
  - Child Welfare - Save the Children Foundation - England, 1930-1941 (Box 46, Folder 509)
    Flyer about "Britain's Children Underground." From Sylvia Warren Committee, London in cooperation with the Save the Children Fund, Inc.
  - Child Welfare - The Children's Village, 1949-1960 (Box 46, Folder 510)
    "Boy on the Police Blotter." Article describing a typical boy's life at The Village.
- Youth Organizations
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brother Movement, 1909-1958 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    Summer camp movement; contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    144
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brother Movement - Contributions, 1927-1945 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Clubs, 1913-1961 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    A few scattered small contributions to local Boys Club units; Laurance S. Rockefeller gift of $10,000 to Newport, Rhode Island Club. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    144.1
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Clubs, 1950-1961 (Box 8, Folder 0075A)
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Clubs - Boys Welfare Association, New York Rotary Club, 1930-1934 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. $2,000 contribution returned to him.
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Clubs - Flatbush Boys Club, 1925-1947 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Organizations and Movements, 1944-1959 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    Descriptions of programs; appeals for contributions all declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, David Freeman.
    144.11
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Organizations and Movements, 1951-1957 (Box 8, Folder 78A)
    Descriptions of programs; most appeals for contributions declined, with one exception being David Rockefeller gift toward American participation in Vienna Youth Festival in 1959. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, David Rockefeller, David Freeman.
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Organizations and Movements, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Organizations and Movements, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 79A)
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Brotherhood Republic, 1940-1958 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    Self-governing boys club activity in New York City; no family interest. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    144.12
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Brotherhood Republic, 1940-1952 (Box 8, Folder 80A)
  - Youth Organizations - Delinquency Studies, 1944-1950 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    Plans for fighting delinquency through homes, farms, concerts; no family interest. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    144.13
  - Youth Organizations - Delinquency Studies, 1947-1950 (Box 9, Folder 81A)
  - Youth Organizations - Delinquency Studies, 1947-1961 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Youth Organizations - Delinquency Studies, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 82A)
  - Youth Organizations - Grand Street Boys' Association, 1933-1960 (Box 9, Folder 83)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, and John D. Rockefeller 3rd were inactive members, made some small contributions. Medal of tribute given to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1942. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    144.14
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Consultation Service, 1933-1961 (Box 9, Folder 84)
    Episcopal service for girls, operates Dana House for unwed mothers. Contributions by Winthrop Rockefeller, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, David Rockefeller. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Mary French Rockefeller.
    144.15
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Consultation Service, 1951-1961 (Box 9, Folder 84A)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brothers of America, 1947-1961 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    Description of work with delinquent and potentially delinquent boys. Appeals declined. Guidebook for Big Brothers. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
    144.16
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brothers of America, 1954-1961 (Box 9, Folder 85A)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brothers of America - Big Brothers, Inc., 1957-1961 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brothers of America - Big Brothers, Inc., 1958-1961 (Box 9, Folder 86A)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brothers of America - Contributions, 1947-1953 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    Contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Youth Organizations - Allied Youth, 1934-1954 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    Organized to discourage liquor drinking by American youth. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Willard S. Richardson, W. R. Breg, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, J. C. Penney.
    144.17
  - Youth Organizations - Girls Vacation Fund, Inc., 1941-1960 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    Forms appeals, ignored. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    144.18
  - Youth Organizations - Yorkville Youth Council, 1948-1961 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    After-school recreational facilities for neighborhood children. Contributions by Mary French Rockefeller and Mary Clark Rockefeller. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    144.19
  - Youth Organizations - Yorkville Youth Council, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Folder 0090A)
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Conservation Bureau, 1913-1941 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    Work similar to Big Brothers: secure homes, education for boys. All appeals declined. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, B. A. Schuman, E. W. Watkins, J. L. Verity.
    144.2
  - Youth Organizations - Camps, 1926-1949 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    Appeals mostly from camps for underprivileged children or other special camps; on or two contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Emmet Hughs, Arthur W. Packard, Willard S. Richardson, John McCormack.
    144.20
  - Youth Organizations - Camps, 1950-1961 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Youth Organizations - Camps, 1954-1960 (Box 10, Folder 0093A)
  - Youth Organizations - International Friendship League, Inc., 1948-1958 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    Related to World Peace Foundation; aimed to stimulate international "penpalism." Christian Herter involved in organization. Small David Rockefeller contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Raymont Dennett, Edna MacDonough.
    144.21
  - Youth Organizations - International Friendship League, Inc., 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 0094A)
  - Youth Organizations - Neighbors United, 1953-1961 (Box 10, Folder 95)
    Juvenile delinquency control project in Lower East Yorkville area. Reports on work; question of Rockefeller Institute involvement. David Rockefeller contributed and recommended that Institute contribute. Participation by Laurance S. Rockefeller, Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Mrs. Roger Greif.
    144.22
  - Youth Organizations - Neighbors United, 1953-1960 (Box 10, Folder 0095A)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Sisters, Inc., 1919-1961 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution to Protestant branch of organization of women helping delinquent girls. Efforts to halt deterioration of program and leadership after World War II; Nelson A. Rockefeller 1951 contribution; Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include Katherine B. David, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Dana S. Creel, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Ivy Lee, Thomas B. Appleget.
    144.3
  - Youth Organizations - Big Sisters, Inc., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 96A)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Sisters, Inc. - Contributions, 1921-1928 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Sisters, Inc. - Contributions, 1929-1962 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Sisters, Inc. - Contributions, 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 98A)
  - Youth Organizations - Big Brother and Sister Federation, 1921-1936 (Box 10, Folder 99)
    Aimed to promote Big Brother movement, standardize work of Big Brothers and Big Sisters; inform public, train workers, secure legislation aiding delinquents. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. conditional pledge to newly created Cooperative Committee was cancelled; contribution by Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial. Professor Glueck's address on prevention of delinquency and crime, his proposed Crime Prevention Institute. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, R. C. Sheldon.
    144.31
  - Youth Organizations - Girls Clubs, 1919-1920 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    Printed material and appeals from National League of Girls Clubs and other groups. David Rockefeller non-recurring $5,000 contribution to Girls Clubs of America. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, David Rockefeller, Mrs. J. J. McCloy.
    144.32
  - Youth Organizations - Girls Clubs, 1918-1961 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Youth Organizations - Girls Clubs, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 0101A)
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club, 45-47 West 53rd Street, 1921-1941 (Box 10, Folder 102)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to club; rental of houses to club; changes in rentals. Club was a residence and dining place for young women working in theatre. Decision to dispose of property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. D. G. Robinson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.
    144.33
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club, 45-47 West 53rd Street - Transfer to Sealantic Fund, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    Letter of gift; conditions.
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club, 1942-1958 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    Sealantic Fund owned property; contribution by family to Club. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller.
    144.34
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 0104A)
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    See also Box 46, Folder 511.
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club, 1955-1961 (Box 11, Folder 0105A)
  - Youth Organizations - Rehearsal Club - Tax Suit, New York City, 1942-1948 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    Property exempted from city tax rolls.
  - Youth Organizations - Brooklyn Juvenile Protective Association, 1919-1946 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    Private organization connected with Children's Court maintains Big Brother type assistance. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions till 1929. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy, Judge Wilkin.
    144.4
  - Youth Organizations - Associated Junior Work Camps, 1939-1944 (Box 11, Folder 108)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller and Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions toward camps offering "useful work experience" for youths. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Club of New York, 1926-1958 (Box 11, Folder 109)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100,000 in 1926; small contributions by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    144.5
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Club of New York, 1941-1958 (Box 11, Folder 0109A)
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Club of New York, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    See also Box 46, Folder 512.
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Club of New York, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 0110A)
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Club of America, 1932-1961 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributions. Other appeals ignored. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
    144.51
  - Youth Organizations - Boys Club of America, 1941-1961 (Box 11, Folder 111A)
  - Youth Organizations - Madison Square Boys' Club, 1930-1961 (Box 11, Folder 112)
    Contributions by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, and John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    144.52
  - Youth Organizations - Boys' Athletic League, 1942-1961 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    All appeals ignored. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    144.53
  - Youth Organizations - Boys' Athletic League, 1950-1960 (Box 12, Folder 113A)
    All appeals ignored. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Youth Organizations - Gramercy Boys' Club, 1934-1961 (Box 12, Folder 114)
    Contributions by Mary French Rockefeller; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    144.54
    See also Box 47, Folder 536.
  - Youth Organizations - Gramercy Boys' Club, 1947-1961 (Box 12, Folder 0114A)
  - Youth Organizations - Hudson Avenue Club for Colored Boys, Brooklyn, 1928-1933 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $4,250 to club in Navy Yard District. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
    144.6
  - Youth Organizations - Kips Bay Boys' Club, 1928-1958 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    Small contributions by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    144.7
  - Youth Organizations - Kips Bay Boys' Club - Nelson A. Rockefeller Correspondence, 1936-1947 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller gave small annual contributions.
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Hostels, 1937-1952 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    144.8
  - Youth Organizations - Youth Hostels, 1939-1940 (Box 12, Folder 0118A)
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels
    No family interest until 1946 when John D. Rockefeller 3rd joined the executive committee as chairman. Reorganization, program, fund raising; Monroe Smith's resignation from organization he had founded. Problems in expanding membership; retrenchment decision. John D. Rockefeller 3rd resignation, 1951. Appeals for contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Monroe Smith, Edgar B. Young, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, B. W. Miller.
    144.81
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1937-1946 (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1950-1951 (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 123)
      See also Box 46, Folder 513.
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 124)
      See also Box 46, Folder 514.
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1951-1961 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1951-1961 (Box 13, Folder 0125A)
    - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels, 1951-1953 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Applicants for Directorship, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    Data on applicants for executive directorship; reports on interview; report on need for executive reorganization; tentative organization charts.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Personnel, 1947-1951 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    Analysis of American Youth Hostels staff jobs; biographical data and appraisals of current staff personnel; suggested candidates; references for American Youth Hostels personnel applying for other jobs.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Arrangement with Miss Shields, 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    Miss Peggy Shields employed as consultant in American Youth Hostels office procedures and fund-raising campaign; campaign recommendations; study of American Youth Hostels income and expenses, 1947-1948. Shields' salary underwritten by John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Committee to Study Objectives of Hosteling, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    Selection of members and chairman.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Taxation, 1950-1951 (Box 13, Folder 131)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd paid for legal services necessary in obtaining tax exemption.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Office Space, 1947-1951 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    Memos and reports regarding present office for headquarters; proposed purchase or rental of various buildings for new executive office.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - E. B. Young California Trip, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    To contact West Coast American Youth Hostels leaders. Post-trip correspondence with and memo regarding West Coast situation and personnel.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Staff Letters and Memos, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    Miscellaneous staff newsletters.
  - Youth Organizations - American Youth Hostels - Directors, 1946-1951 (Box 14, Folder 135)